<!-- Plugin Configuration File. Read more: https://plugins.jetbrains.com/docs/intellij/plugin-configuration-file.html -->
<idea-plugin>
    <!-- Unique identifier of the plugin. It should be FQN. It cannot be changed between the plugin versions. -->
    <id>io.github.palexdev.SessionManager</id>

    <!-- Public plugin name should be written in Title Case.
         Guidelines: https://plugins.jetbrains.com/docs/marketplace/plugin-overview-page.html#plugin-name -->
    <name>SessionManager</name>

    <!-- A displayed Vendor name or Organization ID displayed on the Plugins Page. -->
    <vendor email="alessandro.parisi406@gmail.com"/>

    <!-- Description of the plugin displayed on the Plugin Page and IDE Plugin Manager.
         Simple HTML elements (text formatting, paragraphs, and lists) can be added inside of <![CDATA[ ]]> tag.
         Guidelines: https://plugins.jetbrains.com/docs/marketplace/plugin-overview-page.html#plugin-description -->
    <description><![CDATA[
    A simple plugin that allows to save the current session of the IDE. Open files
    will be stored by default in the .idea folder or in one of the fallback directories if that was not available
    (can be either project directory or user.home directory), or in any other directory of your choice.
    The saved JSON file is then used to restore the saved sessions at any time on any machine (given certain conditions
    further explained below).

    The plugin is very easy to use. Three new options are added in two places: in the Tools menu and in the Tabs
    context menu. All of them have icons to easily distinguish them among the other options.

    - Save Session: this option allows you to save all the currently open tabs to a JSON file named "session-manager.json",
    this name is hard-coded and the plugin will always check for this file in the default directories when first initialized.
    The Session has three parameters: the name, the path and the description. The latter ones are optional. When no path
    is specified the plugin will automatically use one of the default directories (.idea, project directory, user.home).
    As a programmer, I suggest you to use the description wisely. I decided to add it because often I end up forgetting
    where I was and what I was doing, especially if I don't work on the project for some time.
    Last but not least, the plugin also saves the focused tab.
    - Load Session: the plugin has a Map in which sessions are stored. This option allows you to re-load one of those
    sessions previously saved.
    There are two really important things to consider here:
    1) the save action has no limit over the tabs it can record, BUT, the load action will "fail" to load them all if
    the IDE settings do not allow it, before restoring a big session make sure that
    the Editor->General->Editor Tabs->Tabs Limit setting is big enough.
    2) the save action allows you to record any open file, BUT, the intention of this plugin is to help you easily
    save/re-load project files. This means that files that which are external to the project will fail to open.
    - Load Session From File: this action allows you to load any "session-manager.json" file into the plugin. Note that
    this action will not remove any other session already available, however since Sessions are stored like this
    Name->Session, Sessions with the same name will be overwritten!
  ]]></description>

    <!-- Product and plugin compatibility requirements.
         Read more: https://plugins.jetbrains.com/docs/intellij/plugin-compatibility.html -->
    <depends>com.intellij.modules.platform</depends>
    <depends>com.intellij.javafx</depends>

    <!-- Extension points defined by the plugin.
         Read more: https://plugins.jetbrains.com/docs/intellij/plugin-extension-points.html -->
    <extensions defaultExtensionNs="com.intellij">
    </extensions>

    <actions>
        <group id="SessionManager.Menu" text="_Session Manager" description="Session manager">
            <add-to-group group-id="EditorTabPopupMenu" relative-to-action="CopyReference" anchor="after"/>
            <add-to-group group-id="EditorPopupMenu" relative-to-action="CompareClipboardWithSelection"
                          anchor="before"/>
            <add-to-group group-id="ToolsMenu" relative-to-action="Forward" anchor="after"/>
            <separator/>
            <action id="SessionManager.Save" class="io.github.palexdev.sessionmanager.actions.SaveAction"
                    text="Save the Current Session" description="Saves the current session" icon="/icons/save.svg"/>
            <action id="SessionManager.Restore" class="io.github.palexdev.sessionmanager.actions.RestoreAction"
                    text="Restore a Session" description="Restores a previously saved session"
                    icon="/icons/restore.svg"/>
            <action id="SessionManager.LoadFile" class="io.github.palexdev.sessionmanager.actions.LoadFileAction"
                    text="Load Sessions From File"
                    description="Loads previously saved sessions from a compatible json file"
                    icon="/icons/fileLoad.svg"/>
            <separator/>
        </group>
    </actions>
</idea-plugin>